http://aidcomplexity.blogs.casa.ucl.ac.uk robert.g.levy@gmail.com | +44 (0) 7586 340 607

PROFILE

Teacher, facilitator, quantitative researcher, data scientist, visualisation/GIS expert, maths whizz, language-learner and blogger. I'm a genuine mix of techie *and* people person, and enjoy combining these two sides of me in work which is technically challenging, creative, collaborative and communicative.

EXPERIENCE

UCL | PHD AND POSTDOC

May 2012 - Present | London

- Created a new model of the global economy combining input-output models and several trade models
- Worked in Python, using the Pandas data analysis library
- Taught seminars and lectured in Economics and Maths
- Organised and managed project database (around 200 million rows of trade and economic data)
- Facilitated conference sessions at the Royal Society and in the university
- Created interactive web visualisations such as tinyurl.com/rlmodel
- Did some mapping/visualisation work such as tinyurl.com/rlafrica

CITI | DATA ANALYST

Oct 2011 - Mar 2012 | London

• Designed and built Access databases for incremental loading of management information relating to Citibank's transactions worldwide

ALLIANZ GLOBAL INVESTORS | DATA CONSULTANT

Jun 2010 – Sep 2010 | Frankfurt, Germany

- Created a SQL-Server database to store and manage financial data and to generate and record trades made via the Bloomberg financial trading system
- This role was concurrent with my MSc

ACCENTURE | ANALYST

Feb 2008 - May 2009 | London

- SQL Server database design, querying and reporting
- Access front-end design and implementation
- VBA development in Excel and Visio
- Database performance analysis

DATASCOPE RECRUITMENT | DATABASE ENGINEER

July 2007 – Jan 2008 | London

- Database consultancy, design and implementation
- Database front-end design
- Website coding (HTML and CSS)

AWARDS

2013 Outstanding contribution to teaching – Economics dept. UCL
 2009 GRE test – Verbal: 600 (85th %-ile), Quantitative 800 (94th %-ile)
 2007 Certificate of English Language Teaching to Adults (CELTA)

SOCIETIES

2014 Chairman University of London Chamber Choir2014 Performer Bright Club stand-up comedy for academics

SKILLS

CODING

Skilled:

ArcGIS • Python • JavaScript (D3.js data-viz) • Databases (SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL)
Visual Basic • Java • LaTeX
Experience of:
HTML • CSS • PHP • R

TEACHING

Lectured and designed courses in Maths and Economics. CELTA-qualified experienced English teacher.

LANGUAGES

English (native) • German (advanced)French (working proficiency)

EDUCATION

UCL

2012-2015 | London
PHD GLOBAL MATHEMATICAL
MODELLING
Economic modelling, Data,

Economic modelling, Data, Mapping/GIS, Visualisation, Python, Javascript

FRANKFURT UNIVERSITY

MSc QUANTITATIVE ECONOMICS 2011 | Frankfurt, Germany Econometrics, macro, micro Dissertation on natural disasters and economic development.

WARWICK UNIVERSITY

MENG ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING 2004 | UK 2:1

HILLS ROAD COLLEGE

A-LEVELS

Maths, Physics, Chemistry 1999 | Cambridge, UK Three 'A' grades

LINKS

Github://roblevy LinkedIn://robertgrahamlevy StackOverflow://londonrob Twitter://@DataDrivenEcon